SAYO EVERDEN

SayoEverden@gmail.com



+1 (250) 718-2389



github.com/sayo96825 sayo96825.github.io/



ay090025.giti105.io/



www.linkedin.com/in/SayoEverden



A recent graduate from UBC with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with 10+ years of customer service and management experience.

I have just completed the UBC Data Science certificate and Google data analytics professional certificate and I am looking for an opportunity to grow and contribute to the field of information technology.

CERTIFICATION

UBC

- Key Capabilities in Data Science

Google

 Data Analytics Professional Certificate

AWARD

- ★ U.S Presidential Award for Community Service
- ★ Undergraduate Scholarship to UBC Vancouver

LANGUAGE

English

Japanese

SKILLS

- Data Analytics including Python, R, and SQL
- Leadership, Multitasking/Organization, Problem Solving, Data Analysis, Presentation, Public Speaking, Communication, Time Management and Risk Assessment skills with 10+ years of family business and restaurant management experience
- SQL including MySQL, MSSQL, and PostgreSQL
- Data Visualization such as Tableau, Altair, Ggplot, Matplotlib, SciPy and NodeXL
- Data Modeling, Data Collection, Data Wrangling/Mungling, Machine Learning, Data Mining and Social Media Analysis

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science:

2022 University of British Columbia Okanagan, Kelowna

Bachelor of Psychology:

2008 University of British Columbia Okanagan, Kelowna

* Associate of Art with Honor

2003 TransPacific Hawaii College, Honolulu

PROJECT

Capstone Project: LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System)
Led a team of 4 as a project manager to develop the LIMS system from the
ground up for an actual client who was new to software development by
continuously adapting to the change due to the tremendous gap in scope and
limitations of the capstone project.

Direct Study: Social Computing

Proposed a two-phase project on ageism during the covid pandemic. Using the **data analysis research** finding from the first phase, I **developed a social media website** called "Boomer Millennials to facilitate the interaction among generations to close the generation gap.

📊 Social Media Data Analysis Research

Conducted **social media data analysis research** on autism spectrum disorder and social media use.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mini-Ozeki

- Everden Rust Funeral Service Kelowna, BC 2010 - 2020
Office Assistant / Business Analyst

Proposed to open a third location in Westside, BC. Our funeral home has grown from 5 employees with two locations to 10 employees with three locations.

- Restaurant Management /Software Implementation

Implemented a restaurant management software system (Vancouver POS) into five restaurants collaborating with people of more than a dozen nationalities and unique backgrounds.

 Ozeki
 Kelowna, BC
 2006 - Current

 Dozo
 Kelowna, BC
 2017 - 2020

 Osho
 Winfield, BC
 2019

 Basil Leaf
 2018 - Current

Glenmore Kelowna, BC Highway97 Kelowna, BC Peachland Peachland, BC

Kelowna, BC 2022